I have a moral dilemma with electricity.
I do not think that humans should buy
and sell electricity. I don't think it's
theirs. I think it was put here on this
earth by God for all of us to use and
that people have been selling it to you.
[music] And I don't like that. So, I
will give up my time, my energy for free
if I can teach you the only way that I
know right now that you can just snatch
it. The whole purpose of this class is
to teach you how you can design and
figure and install a system on your own.
When else will you get a chance to pick
Parker's brain, my brain, and a NASA
>> engineer's brain?
>> It's kind of funny. You retired and
needed solar for your place. I retired
to a van and needed solar for my place.
And here we are. [music]
>> With no further ado, I'm going to do my
best to explain solar energy as I
understand it. I just call this
simplifying solar cuz the problem is
there's a ton of products and no
information. Who has ever looked up some
type of solar thing on the interwebs?
Did anybody have any relative success
finding clear information? Okay, well,
that changes today. There's a few things
you need to know about solar. Amps *
volts = watts. You must know the
difference between series and parallel
wiring. You have Parker series and
parallel is a big thing, isn't it?
>> Mhm.
>> I will say, guys, all of this stuff is
so simple, but because it's so simple,
it's remarkably easy to mess up. And you
wouldn't think it, but you got a 50/50
chance. There's only a positive and a
negative, but you wouldn't believe how
hard it is to get all the way right
because you have to do very simple
things repetitiously. For energy to
exist, it has to be defined. Energy is
really defined as amps * volts = watts.
And I explain this with a water analogy.